<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>LaCroix Design Co.</title>
  <subtitle>Empowering businesses to become more successful, we design and develop innovative experiences that deliver measurable results.</subtitle>
  <id>http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog</id>
  <link href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog"/>
  <link href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-03-10T16:30:00-05:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>ÉSTAINE's Kickstarter Campaign</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/estaine-kickstarter-campaign/"/>
    <id>http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/estaine-kickstarter-campaign/</id>
    <published>2015-03-10T16:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-03-10T17:03:27-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>James LaCroix</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last year we had the privilege to work with entrepreneurs Zofia Wosinska and Jeremy Picker to design a  &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/case-studies/estaine/"&gt;brand identity&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/case-studies/estaine/"&gt;responsive website&lt;/a&gt; for their new venture, ÉSTAINE. Now they are in the process of utilizing &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/146567895/estaine-science-fashion-impact-shop-smart-fight-ca"&gt;Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt; as a platform to launch their first line of luxury accessories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ÉSTAINE  is using high fashion as a medium to fight cancer. Their Italian-made silk pocket squares, scarves and ties feature the colors and patterns of dyes used in cancer diagnosis. Beyond fashion, these products are intended to educate the community and aid those who are battling cancer. The unique designs are birthed in scientific research yet tell the stories of cancer survivors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 14 days remaining, ÉSTAINE  has already received pledges for over 70% of their goal. However, the project will not be funded unless they receive at least $20,000 in total pledges. Thus, we encourage you to consider supporting their &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/146567895/estaine-science-fashion-impact-shop-smart-fight-ca"&gt;Kickstarter campaign&lt;/a&gt; or visiting the &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.estaine.com/"&gt;ÉSTAINE website&lt;/a&gt; website to learn more. We are excited see everything that ÉSTAINE has in store and thrilled to have been a part of helping them launch their business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="800" height="600" src="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/146567895/estaine-science-fashion-impact-shop-smart-fight-ca/widget/video.html" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/images/blog/estaine-kickstarter-campaign/estaine-kickstarter-campaign-9599810f.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A Study in Craft</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/a-study-in-craft/"/>
    <id>http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/a-study-in-craft/</id>
    <published>2015-02-12T14:30:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-16T18:11:57-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Michael LaCroix</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently we had the opportunity to build a new &lt;a href="/case-studies/chicago-food-magazine/"&gt;responsive website&lt;/a&gt; for a client who had a myriad of short- and long-term goals, many of which would evolve as their vision gained traction. The first objective was to build a publishing platform that would include multiple sets of content types, with isolated author access to entries based on user permissions, the type of content and authorship. Additionally, the pieces of content needed a relational component in order to easily reference each other throughout the many facets of the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the initial requirements and the need to accommodate an array of future unidentified features, we immediately thought of using &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://buildwithcraft.com/"&gt;Craft&lt;/a&gt;. We had used it previously for a handful of smaller projects and absolutely loved the entire experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why Craft?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Craft is a CMS that works wonderfully with structured data, and it doesn’t make any unnecessary assumptions about how that data will be used on the front-end. It provides a head start by supplying the common features needed for a publishing platform such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User accounts and fine-grained permissions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content entry with drafts and versioning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An assortment of built-in field-types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A robust query builder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Routing &amp;amp; pagination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, it has a powerful API to extend its functionality for your project’s specific needs which we’ll be discussing in future blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Publishing User Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s important for us to enjoy building products with Craft, it’s even more important that our clients enjoy using the CMS. Thankfully, the client feedback from previous projects has been excellent. Navigating the CMS’ admin is simple and straightforward, while managing content is extremely easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A feature that was especially loved is the &lt;em&gt;Live Preview&lt;/em&gt; feature, which displays a side-by-side view of the content entry page and the actual output that visitors will see. This is notable because as content and data is entered, this feature of Craft will render the end result as the content changes. Here is Craft’s official promo video of it in action:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class="video"&gt;&lt;iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/111679726?title=0&amp;amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;amp;color=f27390&amp;amp;amp;badge=0" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="true" mozallowfullscreen="true" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Live Preview in action. Really convenient.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Want More?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the project, we created a few libraries to extend Craft’s functionality or connect to external services. The plan is to extract some of these from the project and open source them in the coming weeks. We’ll be following up with more blog posts when we do, as well as tips on Craft configuration and deployment. Check back here or subscribe to our &lt;a href="/newsletter"&gt;monthly newsletter&lt;/a&gt; to receive updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything considered, Craft was a wonderful choice for this project and we highly recommend taking a look at it for your next endeavor. We certainly can’t wait to use it again.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/images/blog/a-study-in-craft/a-study-in-craft-11bd258c.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Always Have a Solid Backup Plan</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/always-have-a-solid-backup-plan/"/>
    <id>http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/always-have-a-solid-backup-plan/</id>
    <published>2015-02-03T07:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-16T18:11:57-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>James LaCroix</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This past autumn, I once again had the opportunity to work with long-time friends and clients, &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://relientk.com"&gt;Relient K&lt;/a&gt; designing and producing merchandise for their upcoming tour. Celebrating the 10-year anniversary of their best-selling album, &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mmhmm"&gt;MMHMM&lt;/a&gt;, the tour was slated to be a special event for both the band and their fans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to newly designed merchandise, the members of Relient K wanted to reprint classic merchandise from the timeframe of their original record release. This led me to an exploration of art files from 10 years back. Many of these files predated LaCroix Design Co. and I was amazed to find that I had retained so many of the design files and records from this time. We were successfully able to manufacture the classic apparel and the tour was a huge success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since starting LaCroix Design Co. in 2005, we have been victims of a burglary and numerous hard drive failures. The fact that I had retained a collection of files from ten years back was more of a testament to luck than any full-proof backup plan. However, we’ve never been content leaving this up to luck alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the beginning, we have made deliberate decisions to ensure that work we create for our clients is systematically backed up and available for years to come. This is an overview of the redundant system we are using to keep all our files safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;System Wide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our backup plan starts with individual computers. This ensures everything on our systems is accessible at any given time. Should we experience a system malfunction, hard drive failure, theft or some other disaster, these backups are available to help us get up and running quickly. These system solutions work in tandem with the other services we outline to provide redundancy.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Time Machine&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We start with &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201250"&gt;Time Machine&lt;/a&gt;, the built-in backup feature of OS X. This feature retains a copy of our of our files, as well as a feature that expresses how our system looked on any given day. These backups are synced via our wireless network and stored on two separate hard drives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Backblaze&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time Machine is a terrific feature, but it is backing up the files to disks which reside at the same physical location as our computers. Thus, we require something that will allow us to backup the bulk of our files to remote storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://lcrx.co/1vplTMd"&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt; excels. For $50 a year, Backblaze will continuously backup an unlimited amount of data from you computer and any drives attached to it. This provides us access to multiple versions of our files through its online interface. Or, we may request the shipment of a hard drive with all of our data on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this backup process is not a fast as a locally attached device or Time Machine running on our local network, Backblaze provides us with a sound piece of mind knowing that our files are continuously being backed up off-site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Design Files&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We find it important to create an additional level of backup for our design files. Very often, these files can be quite large and a loss of the editable versions would require an inordinate amount of time to recreate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;LayerVault&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many years, we stored all of our working design files on Dropbox so that we could access them from anywhere. We have since replaced this with one of my most relied-upon online services, &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://layervault.com/r/3X2"&gt;LayerVault&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LayerVault provides remote version control for all of our art files and a slew of other vital features. Years ago, we attempted to version-control our design files using Git, which resulted in oversized repositories. Thus, we were thrilled to discover that LayerVault offered this crucial service and provided file previews for each version. We no longer have to save versions of a file out as final-1, final-2, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to automatically versioning all of our design files, LayerVault allows us to share project files internally or with an external team. As a result, others involved in a project will always have access to the latest design files and assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, LayerVault retains all of our project files and allows us to leave and rejoin a project at any time. Thus, we are able to remove a folder of project files from our computer and rejoin the project at a later date. Doing so will, in turn, sync all of the design files for a project back to our computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Vault Drive&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an added layer of backup, I keep a large hard drive of every LaCroix Design Co. project connected to my computer. As projects are completed, they are organized in folders by year. Additionally, font files and other assets are regularly archived on this drive. Since the drive is attached to my system, it is also backed up using Backblaze. While I imagine that this drive may one day be replaced by &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://aws.amazon.com/glacier/"&gt;Amazon Glacier&lt;/a&gt; or something similar, but this current setup has been working out very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Development Files&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As our design process evolved from building static designs in traditional design applications to a process of iterating, prototyping and building interactive experiences with code, versioning and keeping backups of development files has become immensely important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Repositories&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of our development projects are version-controlled using &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://git-scm.com/"&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;. We host the majority of these repositories publicly and privately on &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://github.com"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and utilize &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://bitbucket.org/"&gt;Bitbucket&lt;/a&gt; to host repositories for our smaller projects that we wish to keep private.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Documents &amp;amp; Meeting Notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Documents for all projects are stored on &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.google.com/drive/"&gt;Google Drive&lt;/a&gt; and also archived along with all design files onto our Vault Drive upon the completion of each project. &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://lcrx.co/1DylAxU"&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; is used to record all meeting notes, which are then shared internally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it is not obvious by now, our backup process is very important to us. Being able to provide files and assets years after a project is over allows us to continually exceed the expectations of the clients that partner with us. Feel free to &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/lacroixdesign"&gt;comment on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions or need clarity as to how we are using these tools and services.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/images/blog/always-have-a-solid-backup-plan/always-have-a-solid-backup-plan-15958325.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Website Launch: Chicago Food Magazine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/website-launch-chicago-food-magazine/"/>
    <id>http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/website-launch-chicago-food-magazine/</id>
    <published>2015-01-28T15:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-16T18:11:57-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>James LaCroix</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Of all of the things that we enjoy about Chicago, the food scene is probably at the top of the list. By food scene, I’m not referring to Chicago dogs, deep dish or Italian beef. Instead, I’m talking about the fast-growing assortment of new establishments opening by some of the nation’s most notable new chefs and entrepreneurs. When we are not behind our computers or sketching new ideas at our desks, you will most often find us enjoying craft beers, cocktails and/or a delicious meal somewhere that is most likely becoming our new favorite bar or restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can imagine our delight when we began talking with &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.chicagofoodmagazine.com/"&gt;Chicago Food Magazine&lt;/a&gt; back in October. Their team had already begun documenting Chicago’s growing restaurant population through captivating photography. With a vibrant social media presence in place and an ever-growing subscriber base, the team was ready to make their foray into publishing content on their own platform. Their goal was to create an online magazine that provides informative posts on the Chicago food scene in addition to breaking information on news and events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout our correspondence with Chicago Food Magazine, we brainstormed features and devised a plan for a publishing platform that would be able to meet their current goals while also providing a strong foundation for future developments. This platform provides the editorial team with tools to publish articles that include a variety of image and social media elements on the responsive website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our design process produced a scalable visual system that would highlight their rich use of photography and provide a pleasant reading experience for visitors. With a large social media following already in place, an important part of the website’s development involved creating a system for sharing content through those channels. To keep followers informed, breaking news is automatically dispersed across those outlets as articles are published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to have had the opportunity to design and develop the new Chicago Food Magazine website. Even more so, we have thoroughly enjoyed the content that the magazine has been producing since launch. Over the next few weeks, we will be discussing the project in more detail through a series of blog posts as well as a case study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope that you take the opportunity to experience the new website at &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.chicagofoodmagazine.com/"&gt;www.ChicagoFoodMagazine.com&lt;/a&gt; and hopefully we’ll catch you frequenting one of Chicago’s many top-notch establishments.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/images/blog/website-launch-chicago-food-magazine/website-launch-chicago-food-magazine-5777c0b5.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>One Year of Node Bourbon</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/one-year-of-node-bourbon/"/>
    <id>http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/one-year-of-node-bourbon/</id>
    <published>2014-09-11T12:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-16T18:11:57-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Michael LaCroix</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A year ago we released &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/lacroixdesign/node-bourbon"&gt;node-bourbon&lt;/a&gt;, our port of &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://thoughtbot.com/"&gt;thoughtbot&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; excellent &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://bourbon.io/"&gt;Bourbon&lt;/a&gt; library to &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/sass/node-sass"&gt;node-sass&lt;/a&gt;. Node-sass is a Node.js wrapper of &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://libsass.org/"&gt;LibSass&lt;/a&gt;, an extremely fast version of Sass written in C/C++. The original version of Sass is written in Ruby which &amp;mdash; while a wonderful language &amp;mdash; can be a bit slow. With the forthcoming anniversary, we figured it was due time we wrote a blog post about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, Bourbon is a mixin library for &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://sass-lang.com/"&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt;, the popular CSS preprocessor. Bourbon provides a great amount of utility while appreciatively remaining lean and simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why port it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LibSass introduced a dramatic speed increase in Sass compliation that we wanted to take advantage of in our client-side build tools. The original Bourbon was being utilized in our projects for a couple years at that point, however we ran into compilation issues when trying to include it directly since LibSass does not have 100% feature compatibility with Ruby Sass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to create a project which would include workarounds for those issues, while also providing some conveniences for Node.js-based build tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our primary goals for the project were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A focus on LibSass compatibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Packaged for npm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A convenience method for supplying the project path to both the build tool and to other libraries that might depend on it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How to use it&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll provide an example for using node-bourbon in a gulp.js project. Assuming you&amp;rsquo;ve already &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/gulpjs/gulp/blob/master/docs/getting-started.md"&gt;set up gulp&lt;/a&gt;, you&amp;rsquo;ll next want to add node-bourbon to your project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;npm install --save-dev node-bourbon
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then in your &lt;code&gt;gulpfile.js&lt;/code&gt;, use node-bourbon in conjuction with gulp-sass. The &lt;code&gt;includePaths&lt;/code&gt; property returns an array containing the path to the Bourbon directory. Example usage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-scss"&gt;var gulp = require(&amp;#39;gulp&amp;#39;);
var sass = require(&amp;#39;gulp-sass&amp;#39;);

gulp.task(&amp;#39;sass&amp;#39;, function () {
  gulp.src(&amp;#39;path/to/input.scss&amp;#39;)
    .pipe(sass({
      includePaths: require(&amp;#39;node-bourbon&amp;#39;).includePaths
    }))
   .pipe(gulp.dest(&amp;#39;path/to/output.css&amp;#39;));
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have additional paths you would like to load, the &lt;code&gt;with()&lt;/code&gt; helper can assist:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-scss"&gt;var gulp = require(&amp;#39;gulp&amp;#39;);
var sass = require(&amp;#39;gulp-sass&amp;#39;);

gulp.task(&amp;#39;sass&amp;#39;, function () {
  gulp.src(&amp;#39;path/to/input.scss&amp;#39;)
    .pipe(sass({
      includePaths: require(&amp;#39;node-bourbon&amp;#39;).with([&amp;#39;first/path&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;second/path&amp;#39;])
    }))
   .pipe(gulp.dest(&amp;#39;path/to/output.css&amp;#39;));
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples for other tools can be found in the &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/lacroixdesign/node-bourbon#contents"&gt;readme on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/iamlacroix"&gt;send me a tweet&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/images/blog/one-year-of-node-bourbon/bourbon-bb162508.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Announcing Our New Monthly Newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/announcing-our-new-monthly-newsletter/"/>
    <id>http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/announcing-our-new-monthly-newsletter/</id>
    <published>2014-08-26T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-16T18:11:57-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>James LaCroix</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With our inaugural issue nearly complete and subsequent monthly issues already in the works, we are pleased to announce the launch of our new email newsletter. Our first issue will be sent out at the beginning of September and we will be regularly creating original content each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The format will allow us to approach concepts that do not necessarily fit within the structure of our blog or case studies. This will include a behind the scenes look at what we have been building to inspire new ideas and provide benefit to your business. With these curated briefings, we hope to give readers inside access to what we have been researching, designing, building and thinking. We hope this will be a welcome addition to your inbox and encourage you to &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/newsletter/"&gt;subscribe here&lt;/a&gt;.
 
We have worked with numerous clients over the years to design and develop successful email marketing campaigns. As a result, we have consistently been fascinated with finding better ways to connect to an audience through this medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has long been a goal of ours to create our own newsletter. In fact, we have had a form to subscribe on our site for nearly four years. Yet, we have never once sent out a LaCroix Design Co. Newsletter. During this time, we often wrestled with creating valuable email content that our readers would appreciate. As people who regularly receive large amounts of email, we never just wanted to contribute to the noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal with this newsletter is to create something that is candid, genuine and beneficial to our readers. We chose a monthly schedule to ensure that our correspondence is never overwhelming and that the content delivered is relevant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with most things that we do, we also view the creation of our own newsletter as a great opportunity to experiment. We are excited to use &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://eepurl.com/v7UmP"&gt;Mailchimp’s&lt;/a&gt; wonderful tools and features for an internal project. It will also be exciting to evaluate how our readers are engaging with our content as we go along. Thus, we will welcome any feedback and will seek to continually improve with each issue. It is through this ongoing experiment that we look to gain more knowledge, insight and ideas that we will pass along to our current and future clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be sending out the first issue next week. Feel free to subscribe via the form below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class="figure-small"&gt;
  &lt;form action="//lacroixdesign.us2.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=cb74d792445887e99b0a36575&amp;amp;id=9875eb3767"
      id="mc-embedded-subscribe-form"
      class="b-form b-newsletter-form"
      name="mc-embedded-subscribe-form"
      method="post"
      target="_blank"&gt;
  &lt;div class="form__required-indicator"&gt;
    &lt;span class="input--required-asterisk"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; indicates required
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class="input--group theme--text"&gt;
    &lt;label for="mce-EMAIL"&gt;Email Address  &lt;span class="input--required-asterisk"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
    &lt;input type="email" value="" name="EMAIL" id="mce-EMAIL" class="input"&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class="input--group theme--text"&gt;
    &lt;label for="mce-FNAME"&gt;First Name&lt;/label&gt;
    &lt;input type="text" value="" name="FNAME" id="mce-FNAME" class="input"&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class="input--group theme--text"&gt;
    &lt;label for="mce-LNAME"&gt;Last Name&lt;/label&gt;
    &lt;input type="text" value="" name="LNAME" id="mce-LNAME" class="input"&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div style="position: absolute; left: -5000px;"&gt;
    &lt;input type="text" name="b_cb74d792445887e99b0a36575_9875eb3767" tabindex="-1" value=""&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class="b-form__actions"&gt;
    &lt;button type="submit" name="subscribe" class="btn short"&gt;Join&lt;/button&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/images/blog/announcing-our-new-monthly-newsletter/announcing-our-new-monthly-newsletter-ed34674d.jpg"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
