<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>LaCroix Design Co.</title>
  <subtitle>Empowering businesses to become more successful, we design and develop innovative experiences that deliver measurable results.</subtitle>
  <id>http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog</id>
  <link href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog"/>
  <link href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-02-03T07:00:00-06:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Always Have a Solid Backup Plan</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/always-have-a-solid-backup-plan/"/>
    <id>http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/always-have-a-solid-backup-plan/</id>
    <published>2015-02-03T07:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2015-02-03T23:43:05-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>James LaCroix</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This past autumn, I once again had the opportunity to work with long-time friends and clients, &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://relientk.com"&gt;Relient K&lt;/a&gt; designing and producing merchandise for their upcoming tour. Celebrating the 10-year anniversary of their best-selling album, &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mmhmm"&gt;MMHMM&lt;/a&gt;, the tour was slated to be a special event for both the band and their fans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to newly designed merchandise, the members of Relient K wanted to reprint classic merchandise from the timeframe of their original record release. This led me to an exploration of art files from 10 years back. Many of these files predated LaCroix Design Co. and I was amazed to find that I had retained so many of the design files and records from this time. We were successfully able to manufacture the classic apparel and the tour was a huge success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since starting LaCroix Design Co. in 2005, we have been victims of a burglary and numerous hard drive failures. The fact that I had retained a collection of files from ten years back was more of a testament to luck than any full-proof backup plan. However, we’ve never been content leaving this up to luck alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the beginning, we have made deliberate decisions to ensure that work we create for our clients is systematically backed up and available for years to come. This is an overview of the redundant system we are using to keep all our files safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;System Wide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our backup plan starts with individual computers. This ensures everything on our systems is accessible at any given time. Should we experience a system malfunction, hard drive failure, theft or some other disaster, these backups are available to help us get up and running quickly. These system solutions work in tandem with the other services we outline to provide redundancy.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Time Machine&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We start with &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201250"&gt;Time Machine&lt;/a&gt;, the built-in backup feature of OS X. This feature retains a copy of our of our files, as well as a feature that expresses how our system looked on any given day. These backups are synced via our wireless network and stored on two separate hard drives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Backblaze&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time Machine is a terrific feature, but it is backing up the files to disks which reside at the same physical location as our computers. Thus, we require something that will allow us to backup the bulk of our files to remote storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://lcrx.co/1vplTMd"&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt; excels. For $50 a year, Backblaze will continuously backup an unlimited amount of data from you computer and any drives attached to it. This provides us access to multiple versions of our files through its online interface. Or, we may request the shipment of a hard drive with all of our data on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this backup process is not a fast as a locally attached device or Time Machine running on our local network, Backblaze provides us with a sound piece of mind knowing that our files are continuously being backed up off-site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Design Files&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We find it important to create an additional level of backup for our design files. Very often, these files can be quite large and a loss of the editable versions would require an inordinate amount of time to recreate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;LayerVault&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many years, we stored all of our working design files on Dropbox so that we could access them from anywhere. We have since replaced this with one of my most relied-upon online services, &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://layervault.com/r/3X2"&gt;LayerVault&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LayerVault provides remote version control for all of our art files and a slew of other vital features. Years ago, we attempted to version-control our design files using Git, which resulted in oversized repositories. Thus, we were thrilled to discover that LayerVault offered this crucial service and provided file previews for each version. We no longer have to save versions of a file out as final-1, final-2, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to automatically versioning all of our design files, LayerVault allows us to share project files internally or with an external team. As a result, others involved in a project will always have access to the latest design files and assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, LayerVault retains all of our project files and allows us to leave and rejoin a project at any time. Thus, we are able to remove a folder of project files from our computer and rejoin the project at a later date. Doing so will, in turn, sync all of the design files for a project back to our computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Vault Drive&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an added layer of backup, I keep a large hard drive of every LaCroix Design Co. project connected to my computer. As projects are completed, they are organized in folders by year. Additionally, font files and other assets are regularly archived on this drive. Since the drive is attached to my system, it is also backed up using Backblaze. While I imagine that this drive may one day be replaced by &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://aws.amazon.com/glacier/"&gt;Amazon Glacier&lt;/a&gt; or something similar, but this current setup has been working out very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Development Files&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As our design process evolved from building static designs in traditional design applications to a process of iterating, prototyping and building interactive experiences with code, versioning and keeping backups of development files has become immensely important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Repositories&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of our development projects are version-controlled using &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://git-scm.com/"&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;. We host the majority of these repositories publicly and privately on &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://github.com"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and utilize &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://bitbucket.org/"&gt;Bitbucket&lt;/a&gt; to host repositories for our smaller projects that we wish to keep private.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Documents &amp;amp; Meeting Notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Documents for all projects are stored on &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.google.com/drive/"&gt;Google Drive&lt;/a&gt; and also archived along with all design files onto our Vault Drive upon the completion of each project. &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://lcrx.co/1DylAxU"&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; is used to record all meeting notes, which are then shared internally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it is not obvious by now, our backup process is very important to us. Being able to provide files and assets years after a project is over allows us to continually exceed the expectations of the clients that partner with us. Feel free to &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/lacroixdesign"&gt;comment on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions or need clarity as to how we are using these tools and services.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/images/blog/always-have-a-solid-backup-plan/always-have-a-solid-backup-plan-15958325.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Website Launch: Chicago Food Magazine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/website-launch-chicago-food-magazine/"/>
    <id>http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/website-launch-chicago-food-magazine/</id>
    <published>2015-01-28T15:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2015-01-28T15:13:30-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>James LaCroix</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Of all of the things that we enjoy about Chicago, the food scene is probably at the top of the list. By food scene, I’m not referring to Chicago dogs, deep dish or Italian beef. Instead, I’m talking about the fast-growing assortment of new establishments opening by some of the nation’s most notable new chefs and entrepreneurs. When we are not behind our computers or sketching new ideas at our desks, you will most often find us enjoying craft beers, cocktails and/or a delicious meal somewhere that is most likely becoming our new favorite bar or restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can imagine our delight when we began talking with &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.chicagofoodmagazine.com/"&gt;Chicago Food Magazine&lt;/a&gt; back in October. Their team had already begun documenting Chicago’s growing restaurant population through captivating photography. With a vibrant social media presence in place and an ever-growing subscriber base, the team was ready to make their foray into publishing content on their own platform. Their goal was to create an online magazine that provides informative posts on the Chicago food scene in addition to breaking information on news and events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout our correspondence with Chicago Food Magazine, we brainstormed features and devised a plan for a publishing platform that would be able to meet their current goals while also providing a strong foundation for future developments. This platform provides the editorial team with tools to publish articles that include a variety of image and social media elements on the responsive website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our design process produced a scalable visual system that would highlight their rich use of photography and provide a pleasant reading experience for visitors. With a large social media following already in place, an important part of the website’s development involved creating a system for sharing content through those channels. To keep followers informed, breaking news is automatically dispersed across those outlets as articles are published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to have had the opportunity to design and develop the new Chicago Food Magazine website. Even more so, we have thoroughly enjoyed the content that the magazine has been producing since launch. Over the next few weeks, we will be discussing the project in more detail through a series of blog posts as well as a case study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope that you take the opportunity to experience the new website at &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.chicagofoodmagazine.com/"&gt;www.ChicagoFoodMagazine.com&lt;/a&gt; and hopefully we’ll catch you frequenting one of Chicago’s many top-notch establishments.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/images/blog/website-launch-chicago-food-magazine/website-launch-chicago-food-magazine-5777c0b5.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>One Year of Node Bourbon</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/one-year-of-node-bourbon/"/>
    <id>http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/one-year-of-node-bourbon/</id>
    <published>2014-09-11T12:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-01-28T12:44:35-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Michael LaCroix</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A year ago we released &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/lacroixdesign/node-bourbon"&gt;node-bourbon&lt;/a&gt;, our port of &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://thoughtbot.com/"&gt;thoughtbot&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; excellent &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://bourbon.io/"&gt;Bourbon&lt;/a&gt; library to &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/sass/node-sass"&gt;node-sass&lt;/a&gt;. Node-sass is a Node.js wrapper of &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://libsass.org/"&gt;LibSass&lt;/a&gt;, an extremely fast version of Sass written in C/C++. The original version of Sass is written in Ruby which &amp;mdash; while a wonderful language &amp;mdash; can be a bit slow. With the forthcoming anniversary, we figured it was due time we wrote a blog post about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, Bourbon is a mixin library for &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://sass-lang.com/"&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt;, the popular CSS preprocessor. Bourbon provides a great amount of utility while appreciatively remaining lean and simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why port it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LibSass introduced a dramatic speed increase in Sass compliation that we wanted to take advantage of in our client-side build tools. The original Bourbon was being utilized in our projects for a couple years at that point, however we ran into compilation issues when trying to include it directly since LibSass does not have 100% feature compatibility with Ruby Sass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to create a project which would include workarounds for those issues, while also providing some conveniences for Node.js-based build tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our primary goals for the project were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A focus on LibSass compatibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Packaged for npm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A convenience method for supplying the project path to both the build tool and to other libraries that might depend on it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How to use it&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll provide an example for using node-bourbon in a gulp.js project. Assuming you&amp;rsquo;ve already &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/gulpjs/gulp/blob/master/docs/getting-started.md"&gt;set up gulp&lt;/a&gt;, you&amp;rsquo;ll next want to add node-bourbon to your project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash"&gt;npm install --save-dev node-bourbon
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then in your &lt;code&gt;gulpfile.js&lt;/code&gt;, use node-bourbon in conjuction with gulp-sass. The &lt;code&gt;includePaths&lt;/code&gt; property returns an array containing the path to the Bourbon directory. Example usage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-scss"&gt;var gulp = require(&amp;#39;gulp&amp;#39;);
var sass = require(&amp;#39;gulp-sass&amp;#39;);

gulp.task(&amp;#39;sass&amp;#39;, function () {
  gulp.src(&amp;#39;path/to/input.scss&amp;#39;)
    .pipe(sass({
      includePaths: require(&amp;#39;node-bourbon&amp;#39;).includePaths
    }))
   .pipe(gulp.dest(&amp;#39;path/to/output.css&amp;#39;));
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have additional paths you would like to load, the &lt;code&gt;with()&lt;/code&gt; helper can assist:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-scss"&gt;var gulp = require(&amp;#39;gulp&amp;#39;);
var sass = require(&amp;#39;gulp-sass&amp;#39;);

gulp.task(&amp;#39;sass&amp;#39;, function () {
  gulp.src(&amp;#39;path/to/input.scss&amp;#39;)
    .pipe(sass({
      includePaths: require(&amp;#39;node-bourbon&amp;#39;).with([&amp;#39;first/path&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;second/path&amp;#39;])
    }))
   .pipe(gulp.dest(&amp;#39;path/to/output.css&amp;#39;));
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples for other tools can be found in the &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/lacroixdesign/node-bourbon#contents"&gt;readme on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/iamlacroix"&gt;send me a tweet&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/images/blog/one-year-of-node-bourbon/bourbon-bb162508.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Announcing Our New Monthly Newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/announcing-our-new-monthly-newsletter/"/>
    <id>http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/announcing-our-new-monthly-newsletter/</id>
    <published>2014-08-26T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-01-28T12:44:35-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>James LaCroix</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With our inaugural issue nearly complete and subsequent monthly issues already in the works, we are pleased to announce the launch of our new email newsletter. Our first issue will be sent out at the beginning of September and we will be regularly creating original content each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The format will allow us to approach concepts that do not necessarily fit within the structure of our blog or case studies. This will include a behind the scenes look at what we have been building to inspire new ideas and provide benefit to your business. With these curated briefings, we hope to give readers inside access to what we have been researching, designing, building and thinking. We hope this will be a welcome addition to your inbox and encourage you to &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/newsletter/"&gt;subscribe here&lt;/a&gt;.
 
We have worked with numerous clients over the years to design and develop successful email marketing campaigns. As a result, we have consistently been fascinated with finding better ways to connect to an audience through this medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has long been a goal of ours to create our own newsletter. In fact, we have had a form to subscribe on our site for nearly four years. Yet, we have never once sent out a LaCroix Design Co. Newsletter. During this time, we often wrestled with creating valuable email content that our readers would appreciate. As people who regularly receive large amounts of email, we never just wanted to contribute to the noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal with this newsletter is to create something that is candid, genuine and beneficial to our readers. We chose a monthly schedule to ensure that our correspondence is never overwhelming and that the content delivered is relevant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with most things that we do, we also view the creation of our own newsletter as a great opportunity to experiment. We are excited to use &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://eepurl.com/v7UmP"&gt;Mailchimp’s&lt;/a&gt; wonderful tools and features for an internal project. It will also be exciting to evaluate how our readers are engaging with our content as we go along. Thus, we will welcome any feedback and will seek to continually improve with each issue. It is through this ongoing experiment that we look to gain more knowledge, insight and ideas that we will pass along to our current and future clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be sending out the first issue next week. Feel free to subscribe via the form below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class="figure-small"&gt;
  &lt;form action="//lacroixdesign.us2.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=cb74d792445887e99b0a36575&amp;amp;id=9875eb3767"
      id="mc-embedded-subscribe-form"
      class="b-form b-newsletter-form"
      name="mc-embedded-subscribe-form"
      method="post"
      target="_blank"&gt;
  &lt;div class="form__required-indicator"&gt;
    &lt;span class="input--required-asterisk"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; indicates required
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class="input--group"&gt;
    &lt;label for="mce-EMAIL"&gt;Email Address  &lt;span class="input--required-asterisk"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
    &lt;input type="email" value="" name="EMAIL" id="mce-EMAIL" class="input"&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class="input--group"&gt;
    &lt;label for="mce-FNAME"&gt;First Name&lt;/label&gt;
    &lt;input type="text" value="" name="FNAME" id="mce-FNAME" class="input"&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class="input--group"&gt;
    &lt;label for="mce-LNAME"&gt;Last Name&lt;/label&gt;
    &lt;input type="text" value="" name="LNAME" id="mce-LNAME" class="input"&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div style="position: absolute; left: -5000px;"&gt;
    &lt;input type="text" name="b_cb74d792445887e99b0a36575_9875eb3767" tabindex="-1" value=""&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class="b-form__actions"&gt;
    &lt;button type="submit" name="subscribe" class="btn"&gt;Subscribe&lt;/button&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/images/blog/announcing-our-new-monthly-newsletter/announcing-our-new-monthly-newsletter-ed34674d.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lessons Learned From Working Remotely</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/lessons-learned-from-working-remotely/"/>
    <id>http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/lessons-learned-from-working-remotely/</id>
    <published>2014-08-19T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-01-28T12:44:35-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>James LaCroix</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;From day one, my business has been a laboratory for experimentation. My time spent working in the music industry piqued my interest in entrepreneurship and small business ventures, but I initially knew very little about running a design studio. With no previous experience as a design employee, my company was a blank canvas for how a design studio could be run. Of course, this has resulted in plenty of mistakes and hard lessons but over time, I&amp;rsquo;ve continually welcomed the opportunity to experiment with all aspects of the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same manner that we use design thinking to deliver successful solutions for our clients, we believe that design thinking can be applied to the process that leads us to those results. Experimentation and iteration provides continual improvement in the way we operate. One such experiment meant moving my company nearly 500 miles from Nashville to Chicago. The relocation provided us with an opportunity to move out of our comfort zone in order to improve as designers and developers. It also made me grow as a business owner. Leaving a small market where my business was established and operating successfully to a much larger market where we would be virtually unknown offered its fair share of opportunities and risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ease the transition, Michael remained in Nashville for a year and we began working remotely. Operating out of separate locations meant that we had to adjust our workflows to ensure that the quality of our work would not slip but rather improve as we began to enter a larger market. As with any new experiment, our foray into remote work had its bumps and bruises. Before long, we had adapted and found ourselves relishing in our newfound workflows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twelve months ago, this year-long experiment came to an end as Michael made the move to Chicago so that we could once again work within the same office. Now, with a full year of working beside one another, we have realized that the lessons learned from working remotely have made us better designers, developers and communicators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We became better writers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Remote work eliminated the opportunity for casual conversation. Phone calls and video chats consume too much time so we chose to limit those to important occasions. Writing became our main source of communication. This required articulation with our thoughts in order to get our points across clearly and efficiently. Whether using email, project management software or our internal chat software, working remotely demanded deliberate thought when sharing our ideas and critiques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In turn, this helped with client correspondence as well. We devised systems for reviewing and editing proposals or any long-form communications with clients. This required that initial contributor took the time to encompass all of the finer details of the project so that the reviewer would be able to provide edits that helped to clarify the material. Often, we would review documents several times to assure that our correspondence represented the same thoughtfulness that we give to our work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We had to be more organized.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
When working remotely, little things that slip through the cracks can&amp;rsquo;t happen. Thus, we had to develop a bulletproof set of systems that we still use today. Completed tasks needed to be recorded so that both partners were keenly aware of what needed to be accomplished. Additionally, keeping files and resources organized was crucial for streamlined workflow at both offices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We relied on our project management software to meet these needs. The tool that we were already using, &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://basecamp.com/"&gt;Basecamp&lt;/a&gt;, was our initial solution. Utilizing email as its notification channel, Basecamp allowed us to also bring clients into the project management software. This way, our clients could observe and communicate as their project was progressing. We have since progressed to using &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://trello.com/jameslacroix/recommend"&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; for all internal projects and have begun testing it on some client projects. Trello provides us with a more visual view of the project status. Additionally, tasks can proceed through a series of stages rather than simply complete or incomplete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While working in remote offices, we still needed to have a channel for regular conversation &amp;mdash; enter chat service. We initially used &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://campfirenow.com/"&gt;Campfire&lt;/a&gt;, followed by &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.hipchat.com/"&gt;Hipchat&lt;/a&gt; and then happily landed on &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://slack.com/r/024l00bf-02533q4k"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;. To this day, the majority of our conversations still take place in Slack. The service provides separate channels to keep our thoughts organized and the ability to search through these communications at a later time. Seamlessly working with third-party applications, Slack will notify us of Trello updates or Git commits. It will also parse the information from shared links which allow us to quickly share screenshots of ideas using &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.getcloudapp.com/"&gt;CloudApp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We learned to be more decisive.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
One of the fallbacks of being a designer or developer is overthinking our solutions. We are all guilty of this from time to time. Self-doubt will sometimes creep in and minor iterations end up consuming hours of work only to return to where you first started. When working in the same office, it is quite convenient to distract a co-worker for feedback on every little step. In this circumstance, self-doubt begins to paralyze your workflow. Working remotely required proactive and confident decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, this experiment in working remotely has had a lasting, positive
effect on our non-remote workflows. After working in the
same office for a year now, we&amp;rsquo;ve found that these changes have improved the productivity and quality of our work.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/images/blog/lessons-learned-from-working-remotely/lessons-learned-from-working-remotely-8efd083e.jpg"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keeping Workplace Morale High</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/keeping-workplace-morale-high/"/>
    <id>http://www.lacroixdesign.net/blog/keeping-workplace-morale-high/</id>
    <published>2014-05-29T16:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2015-01-28T12:44:35-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>James LaCroix</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;figure class="image-stretch-wrap"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dempsey" class="image-fullwidth" width="800" height="800" src="http://www.lacroixdesign.net/images/blog/keeping-workplace-morale-high/dempsey-office-f7fe3a92.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love designing and developing for the web. However, there are those rare times when even things that we are passionate about start to feel like hard work. It is for these times that we have recruited the smallest member of our team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Named after a &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://cloud.lacroixdesign.net/image/1P2q2o030G0V"&gt;popular United States soccer star&lt;/a&gt;, Dempsey is tasked with keeping the workplace morale high. She often accomplishes this by launching herself into laps, engaging workers in playful activities or performing hilarious antics. While not condoned in some workplaces, Dempsey is also known to dish out quite gratuitous displays of affection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to keeping morale high, Dempsey fills her day by performing security detail and ensuring that office seating remains occupied if someone goes out to make a coffee. In typical Don Draper-esque fashion, she is quite keen to take an office nap in order to keep the creative juices flowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not know how we got by before this rescued Schnauzer puppy joined us. Aside from piping in on the occasional phone call, most of Dempsey&amp;rsquo;s contributions go unnoticed by those outside of our small design and development team. However, she has become integral part of our inner workings and we figured that it was about time to give credit where credit was due.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
